你刚刚说是瑞秋吗
I'm sorry, did you just say it's Rachel?
对
Yes.
你喜欢瑞秋
You like Rachel?
对  我喜欢瑞秋
Yes. I like Rachel.
瑞秋
Rachel?!
对  听着  你知道的
Yeah. Okay, but look, you know...
你知道我还喜欢谁吗  你
You know who else I like? You.
这句话我说得不够多  我喜欢你  罗斯
And it doesn't get said enough. I like you, Ross.
-那个"瑞秋"  -没什么大不了的
- "Rachel" Rachel? - It's not a big deal.
没什么大不了的  抱歉  我只是...
It's not a big deal? I'm sorry, I just...
那你刚刚说的那些话呢
What about the stuff you said?
你说你没法不去想她
How you can't stop thinking about her?
你说你睡不着
How you can't sleep?
我是个演员  你知道吗
I'm an actor, you know?
我们演员习惯了夸大事实
As a group, we tend to be overdramatic.
怀着我孩子的瑞秋
Rachel-who's-carrying-my-baby Rachel?
我知道这样很不好  这样是不对的  好吗
I know it's bad. And I know it's wrong, okay?
但我们不可能在一起啊
But it's not like anything's ever gonna happen.
那只是我的一时好感  会慢慢变淡的
These are just feelings. They'll go away.
我得走了
You know, I gotta go.
别这样  罗斯
Hey, come on, Ross...
我只是...  我只有一个...  瑞秋
I just... You know, I just have one... Rachel?!
瑞秋
Rachel?!
她在踢我
Okay, she's kicking.
她在你的体内成长
She's growing inside you.
这一下踢得好用力
That was a big one.
她是拒绝过我最年轻的女孩
I think that's the youngest girl ever to reject me.
-大家好  -嗨
- You guys! - Hey there.
我来问你们  你们相信有灵魂伴侣吗
Listen let me ask you. Do you believe in soul mates?
我相信
Oh, yes, I do.
我认为每个人都有
I do. I believe that there is one perfect person
失落的另一半
out there for everyone.
你知道你该怎么找到他吗  停下寻找的步伐
You know how you find him? You stop looking for him.
所以我已经不去费劲寻找罗素·克洛了[演员]
That's why I stopped looking for Russell Crowe.
他会找到我的
He'll find me.
你呢
And you?
不  我相信有些人彼此适合
No. I believe that certain people are more suited for each other,
我也相信两人可以相爱  但...
and I believe in falling in love, but...
-我不相信存在灵魂伴侣  -很好
- Soul mates? I don't think they exist. - Okay, good.
-怎么了  -昨晚我遇到了莫妮卡的灵魂伴侣
- Why? - Well, last night, I met Monica's.
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yeah.
跟我约会的那个男人
I had a date with this guy.
我发誓他是她的另一半
And I swear to god he's her other half.
别犯傻了  你不觉得会有人
Come on, don't be crazy. You don't think there's somebody out there
比我更适合莫妮卡吧
better suited for Monica than me, do you?
他长什么样子
Well, what's he like?
-他很高  棕发  -当然
- He's tall. He has brown hair. - Of course.
一个发色跟我一样的高大男人
A tall guy with hair similar to mine?
宇宙真的神秘莫测
Oh, unknowable universe!
他从事跟食物相关的行业
He works with food.
当然  年纪比较大吗
Oh, sure. Older?
没错  他是英国人
Obviously. And he's British.
-我正打算要问你  -是啊
- I was just gonna ask! - Yeah.
他非常聪明  成熟  有自信
And he's so centered, and mature and confident.
真可惜他们彼此不认识
It's so sad they never had a chance to meet.
还好她老公没听到你说这种话
Luckily, the guy she settled for can't hear what you're talking about.
抱歉  我可能搞错了
Oh, I'm so sorry. Maybe I'm wrong.
我会再跟他约会  对他进一步了解
I'm gonna go out with him again. I'll find out more.
你明明觉得他跟别人是天生一对
You believe that this guy is destined for someone else
你还要跟他约会
and you're still gonna date him?
虽说他不是我的灵魂伴侣  但我总得吃饭吧
He may not be my soul mate, but a girl's gotta eat.
我刚跟乔伊谈过  我想知道你好不好
I just talked to Joey. I wanted to see you how you were.
我还是不敢相信  乔伊跟瑞秋
I still can't believe it. Joey and Rachel?
就像是你跟我交往  只不过更奇怪
It's like you and me going out, only weirder.
我知道你很难过  我也想安慰你...
I know you're hurting, and I want to be supportive,
但别再说那种话了
...but don't say that again.
他们要是结婚了怎么办
Oh, my god. What if they get married?
他可能做我孩子的继父
He'd be the stepfather of my child.
我觉得你不必担心这种事情
Honey, I don't think that's something we need to worry about!
他不会把自己的感觉告诉她
First of all, he'll never tell her how he feels about her.
就算他说了 你也不知道她会有什么反应
And even if he did, you have no idea how she'd react.
女人从来就不喜欢乔伊  我觉得他还是处男
Sure, women never like Joey. I think he's a virgin.
-他根本就没想过要追瑞秋  -真的吗
- Joey isn't even thinking about going after Rachel. - He's not?
对  他关心的是你对此事的反应
No, all he's thinking about is how you're taking this.
这件事把他吓坏了
Listen, it's completely freaking him out.
他甚至想搬到佛蒙特州去
He's talking about moving to Vermont.
-为什么  -他想离开这个国家
- Why? - He says he wants to leave the country.
他觉得你恨他
He thinks you hate him.
恨他
Hate him?
不  我不恨他
No, I don't hate him.
那可是瑞秋  你知道吗
It's just, it's Rachel. You know?
我无法想像你有多难过...
I can't even imagine how hard this must be for you...
但我不希望你跟乔伊因此做不成朋友
...but I don't want you to lose Joey over it.
现在他想知道你是不是还把他当朋友
Right now, he just needs to know that you're still his friend.
好吧  我会跟他谈
Okay, I'll talk to him.
你最好快去
Do it soon.
他刚刚问我怎么把美金换成佛蒙特货币
He just asked me how to convert his dollars into Vermont money.
-钱德勒  莫妮卡  他是唐  -你们好
- Chandler, Monica, this is Don. - Hello.
你好  幸会
Hello, nice to meet you.
-你好吗  -灵魂伴侣
- How are you? - Soul mate.
你们刚才有什么活动
So, what have you guys been doing?
我们在艾德瑞提卡吃了顿难以下咽的午餐
Well, we just had a terrible lunch today at Adriatica.
那家餐厅的番茄干是怎么回事
What's with the sun-dried tomatoes in that place?
就是  难道现在还是1985年吗
I know! Is this 1985?
我就是那么说的  菲比  这很奇怪吧
That's exactly what I said. Phoebe, isn't that strange.
一点都不会
Not really.
番茄干怎么了
What's wrong with sun-dried tomatoes?
洒在烤鸡披萨上
On a barbecued-chicken pizza?
不是吗
No?
唐  你还喜欢哪家餐厅
So, Don. What other restaurants do you like?
奥克塔维欧  27与7
Octavio. 27-and-7.
还有亚利山多洛斯
There's this great little place, Alessandro's.
天啊  我是那里的主厨
Oh, my God! That's my restaurant, I'm the chef there.
开玩笑吧  你做的菜好吃极了
You're kidding me! Your food is fantastic!
我要跟你谈谈你的菜单
I really want to talk about your menu,
我先去买杯咖啡  还有人要喝吗
once I get some coffees first. Um, anyone want any?
我要喝拿铁
Oh, I'd like a latte.
如果你要谈我的事
You know what? If you're gonna talk about me,
我就跟你一起去
I'm gonna go with you.
你这是要干什么
What are you doing?
我发誓我不知道你们在这里
Nothing. I swear to god, I didn't know you guys would be here.
还好你不相信灵魂伴侣  所以
And the good news is you don't even believe in soul mates, so...
但我相信英俊的陌生人要追我老婆
I believe in tall, handsome strangers who hit on my wife.
他们不过是聊天而已
They're just talking, and you know what?
就算我认为他们是灵魂伴侣
Just because I think they're soul mates
那也不代表会发生什么事
doesn't mean anything'll happen.
菲比  做得好
Phoebe? Good work.
他太棒了  我爱他
He's great. I love him.
别担心  我们会帮你再找个老婆
Don't worry, we'll find you someone else.
如果你是来打我的  我能理解  这是我活该
I understand if you came by to hit me. I deserve it.
不  我不想打你
No, I don't want to hit you.
怎么  你要踢我
What, then? Kick me?
不
No.
咬我
Bite me?
我不想对你怎么样
I don't want to do anything to you.
我只想告诉你  我没有生你的气
I just want to tell you that I'm not mad at you...
我当然也不恨你
...and that I certainly do not hate you.
我只是来告诉你这些
I just came here to say that.
等一下  罗斯
Hey, wait, Ross, Ross?
你想进来喝瓶啤酒吗
You wanna come in for a beer or something?
好吧
Yeah, sure.
你带啤酒了吗
You got any beer?
我只有瑞秋留下的香瓜饮料
All I got is melon stuff that Rachel left.
好吧
Okay.
罗斯  有件事你得知道
Look, Ross. You need to understand something, okay?
我...
I...
我绝不会对瑞秋采取行动  好吧
I am never gonna act on this Rachel thing, okay?
我不会做出任何会危及你我友谊的事
I wouldn't do anything to jeopardize my friendship with you.
谢谢
Thank you.
总之  我只是...
Anyway, it'll just...
我得花点时间去淡忘
It'll take me a while to get over her, that's all.
我不确定我该怎么做
I'm not even sure how to do that,
我以前从没陷入过爱河  所以
I mean I've never been in love before, so...
什么
What?
你爱上她了吗
You're in love with her?
-对  我以为你知道  -不知道
- Yeah. I thought you knew that. - No.
听着  如果有帮助的话
Look, if it helps,
我真的也不希望自己有那种感觉
I don't want to feel this way, honest.
我只是一直在想
I just keep thinking,
"我得忘了这件事"  你知道吗
"I'll get over this," you know?
但我越努力就越忘不了
But it just keeps getting harder.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do, you know?
我该怎么办
I don't... What do I do?
我觉得你该告诉她你的感觉
I think you need to tell her how you feel.
你一定是被这饮料冲昏了头
Okay, that's the green stuff talking.
我是认真的  你得知道她的感觉
No, I'm serious. You need to find out where she is.
如果她不喜欢你
Because if she's not where you are,
你就可以放下了
then you can start to move past this.
但如果...  我不是说她会这么说
But what if, and I'm not saying she will be...
如果她喜欢你...
If she is where you are, then...
那我的感受不该妨碍到你们
...then my feeling weird shouldn't stand in the way.
-你确定  -对
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
如果她要跟别的男人在一起...
Look, if she's gonna end up with somebody else...
说真的  她找不到更好的人选了
...the truth is, she couldn't find a better guy, so...
谢谢
Hey, thanks.
你准备什么时候要跟她谈
So when do you think you're gonna talk to her?
天啊  我得跟她谈
Oh, my God. I have to tell her.
我还没有想过  我该说什么
I haven't thought about what I will say. What should I say?
我能体谅你  但不要太过激动了
I'm understanding, but let's not get carried away.
抱歉
I'm sorry. Sorry.
我该说什么
What am I gonna say?
我也觉得超难喝
Yeah, tell me about it.
我逐渐放弃了红酒进口的问题
So I've been slowly phasing out the wine importing
现在全力研究奶酪
and focusing more on the cheese side of things.
你说奶酪吗
Cheese, you say?
这研究起来可真够臭气熏天的  唐
That's some pretty smelly work, huh, Don?
-对不起  -奶酪很臭
- Excuse me? - Cheese. It's smelly.
你一定也经常臭气四溢
You must smell a lot of the time too.
不会的  但我觉得奶酪
Not really. But when it comes to cheese,
越臭越好
I'm one of the people who thinks the smellier, the better.
我也是  钱德勒就受不了
Me too! Chandler can't stand it.
他都不让我在家吃蓝纹奶酪
He won't even allow me to have blue cheese in the house.
那你还嫁给了他
And you're still married to him?
知道我想干嘛吗
You know what I'd love to do?
我想去法国  只吃面包跟奶酪
I would like to go to France and eat nothing but bread and cheese.
甚至连面包都不吃  只要奶酪
Not even bread. Just cheese.
不  我要面包
No, I want the bread.
还有油酥饼
And pastries.
跟小蛋糕
And pate.
我并不是真的兴奋  只是以前我很胖
I'm really not high. It's just I used to be fat.
我在罗亚尔谷有栋别墅
Well if you where ever enter the Loire valley let me know,
你如果去法国可以住在那里
I've got a great little villa you can stay at.
是用奶酪做的吗
Is it made of cheese?
不是  不过用奶酪做的房子  简直宛如天堂
No. A house made of cheese, wouldn't that be incredible?
-我明天就想搬进去  -少来了
- I'd move in tomorrow! - Oh, come on!
-你听到了吗  -对不起
- Are you listening to this! - I'm so sorry.
-我们该怎么办  -我不知道
- What do we do? - I don't know.
他们都想住在奶酪屋里
They both want to live in a house of cheese.
我不知道你该拿什么去抗争
I don't know how you fight that.
好吧  我能做到
Okay, okay. I can do this.
我可以告诉她我的感觉
I can tell her how I feel.
好吧  挺直腰杆
Okay, stand up straight.
深呼吸
Take a couple deep breaths.
表现出自信
Look confident.
乔伊  怎么了
Joey? What's up?
我来找你  是想告诉你一件事
I just came by because I want to talk to you about something.
怎么了
Okay. What's up?
就在走廊上谈  我们是畜生吗
Here, in the hall? What are we, animals?
我开会要迟到了  你能快点说吗
I'm late for a meeting. Could you make it quick?
我是来告诉你...
I just came by to tell you that...
我今天想跟你一起吃晚餐
...I want to have dinner with you tonight.
没问题
Sure. That sounds great!
给我留言  告诉我到哪里找你
Just leave me a message and tell me where to meet you. Okay?
好吧  这样也不错
Okay. That's good.
这又给你几小时的时间
Okay, that give you a couple hours
准备好谈话内容  不错
to prepare what you're gonna say. Good. Yeah.
你们就不会敲门吗
Don't you people ever knock?
我想请唐跟菲比过来
I'd like to have Don and Phoebe over.
-不错吧  -没问题  你去安排吧
-Wouldn't that be nice? - Sure. Why don't you set it up?
我就坐着看看征婚广告
I'll just be over here browsing through the personals.
你没事吧  你有点怪怪的
Are you okay? You're acting weird all afternoon.
没事  算不上心情大好
Yeah. Fine. Not perfect.
但也很不错了
But good enough.
天啊  你这是怎么了
Jeez, what's with you?
抱歉  你刚刚说"奶酪"吗
I'm sorry, did you say "cheese"?
怎么了
All right. What's going on?
菲比说你跟唐是灵魂伴侣
Phoebe thinks you and Don are soul mates.
我不迷信那种事情
I don't believe in that kind of stuff,
但你们两个一拍即合
but then you two totally get along.
如果你想跟唐住在奶酪屋里
So, look, I won't stand in your way if you wanna run off with Don
我可以退出
and live in a house of cheese.
钱德勒  你不相信灵魂伴侣
Chandler, you don't believe in soul mates?
对  但我相信"番茄干先生"相信
No, but I'm sure "tomahtoes" does.
我也不相信灵魂伴侣
I don't believe in soul mates, either.
-你不相信吗  -对
- You don't? - Nope.
我觉得我们并非注定要在一起
I don't think you and I were destined to end up together.
而是陷入爱河  努力经营我们的感情
I think that we fell in love and work hard at our relationship.
有时候要加倍努力经营
Some days we work really hard.
那你不想跟唐住在奶酪屋里吗
So you don't want to live with Don in a cheese house?
不  我后来又仔细想了一下
No, I've had second thoughts about that.
你知道打扫起来有多辛苦吗
Do you realize how hard it'd be to clean?
-我爱你  -我知道
- I love you. - I know.
我今晚要带你去吃晚餐
You know what? I'm gonna take you out to dinner tonight.
那家餐馆的墨西哥辣椒卷
I found this place that makes the greatest mozzarella sticks
天下无双
and jalepino poppers.
不吃吗  真的很好吃
No? Really? They taste so good.
我知道钱德勒只是开玩笑
And I know Chandler is kidding,
但他每次一摸我的肚子就会这样
but it happens whenever he touches my stomach.
我真的担心宝宝不喜欢他
I mean I'm really worried the baby won't like him.
-你没事吧  -没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah, sure.
听着  我之所以...
Look, the reason...
这里很热吗
Is it hot in here?
我不觉得  不过你可以把毛衣脱掉
Not for me, but why don't you take off your sweater?
我也想  但这个地方挺上档次
I would, but this is a nice place...
而我的T恤上印了卡尔文干荷比丝的图案
...and my T-shirt has a picture of Calvin doing Hobbes.
天啊  真的吗  我能看一下吗
Oh, my God, really? Can I see it?
当然可以
Yeah, sure.
我觉得荷比丝可不想那么"干"
I wouldn't think Hobbes would like that so much.
我们认识多久了
How long have we known each other?
七  八...
Seven, eight...
八年了
Eight years. Wow.
-真的很久了  -是啊
- A long time. - Yeah.
但过去几星期以来我...
But over the past few weeks, I...
好吧  抱歉让你们久等  今天客人真的很多
Okay! Sorry about the wait, but it is mega-jammed in here.
今晚的特餐是...
We have a couple specials tonight...
-你能等一下再来吗  -好吧
- Actually could you give us a second? - Sure.
时间到
Second's up!
你们不是那种能开玩笑的客人
Not that kind of table.
你要说什么
So you were saying?
我不确定
I'm not quite sure.
你问我们认识了多久
Okay. You asked how long we knew each other,
我说八年
and I said eight years.
后来服务生走过来  害他损失了一半的小费
Then the waiter came over and cut his tip in half...
我们就说到这里了
...and now here we are.
没错
Yeah. Here we are.
我...
I...
我想我爱上你了
I think I'm falling in love with you.
什么
What?
我爱上你了
I'm falling in love with you.
你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
你在开玩笑  这是闹着玩的
Oh, you're kidding. It's a joke.
真的很好笑
Funny. It's funny!
我没找到笑点
I don't get it.
好吧
Okay.
你...
Are you...?
怎么会...
How did...?
什么时候
When?
那真的重要吗
Does it really matter?
这里确实好热
It is hot in here.
我知道这很难接受
Rach, I know this is a lot.
你什么都不必说
You don't have to say anything.
你要花多少时间思考都可以
You take as much time as you need.
好吧  你得说句话
Okay, you gotta say something.
乔伊  我非常爱你
Joey, Joey, I love you so much.
-但是...  -但是
- But... - But.
乔伊
Joey?
对  那...
Right. Hey, that's...
没关系  真的
That's okay. That's fine.
我早就料到你会这样
It's pretty much what I was expecting.
那没什么大不了的  好吗
So it's no big deal, all right?
我觉得我该走了
I think I'm gonna go.
乔伊  请不要这样离开
No, Joey. Please don't leave like this.
你不能这样对一个孕妇
You can't do this to a pregnant woman!
别哭了
Don't start doing that.
你不能那么做  瑞秋  你都要把我弄哭了
You can't do that, Rach, because you're gonna make me...
我们一起哭吧
Oh, there we go!
-可以吗  -没问题
- Can I? - Sure.
乔伊  我不想失去...
Oh, Joey. I don't want to lose...
不会的  好吗  永远不会
You can't, okay? Ever.
-我真的很抱歉  -别这样  瑞秋
- I'm so sorry. - No, no, no, Rach.
请你不要那么说
Please don't be sorry.
好吧  别感到抱歉
Okay? Don't be sorry.
我只是在开玩笑
You know, I was only kidding.
对  这个笑话很搞笑
Yeah, that was a real good one.
-他们是你的客人  -对
- Is this your table? - Yeah.
-你得在这里待上一整晚了  -我知道
- God, you'll be here all night. - I know.
我连特餐内容都还没有介绍
I haven't even read them the specials yet.
他们怎么了
What's the matter with them?
我不知道  可能他们有人快死了
I don't know. I think maybe one of them is dying.
我希望是那个女的
I kind of hope it's the girl.
那个男的真的很帅
The guy is really cute!